<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>vblinden</title><link>https://vblinden.nl/</link><description>Recent content on vblinden</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© vblinden</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 23:24:13 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://vblinden.nl/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to install AMQP on macOS</title><link>https://vblinden.nl/posts/how-to-install-amqp-on-macos/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 23:24:13 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://vblinden.nl/posts/how-to-install-amqp-on-macos/</guid><description>I recently wanted to install the AMQP extension for PHP version 7.4, but ran into some issues on macOS.
It should be as easy as running the following commands:
brew install rabbitmq-c pecl install amqp Unfortunately I ran into the following issues:
Warning: mkdir(): File exists in System.php on line 294 PHP Warning: mkdir(): File exists in /usr/local/Cellar/php/7.4.10/share/php/pear/System.php on line 294 Warning: mkdir(): File exists in /usr/local/Cellar/php/7.3.3/share/php/pear/System.php on line 294 ERROR: failed to mkdir /usr/local/Cellar/php/7.</description></item><item><title>What did you undesign?</title><link>https://vblinden.nl/posts/what-did-you-undesign/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 21:21:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://vblinden.nl/posts/what-did-you-undesign/</guid><description>In the video above Eric Berger from Ars Technica asks the question on how Elon Musk and the team at SpaceX build the iteration of Starship within 4/5 months and how they&amp;rsquo;d go so fast. Here is the transcript for those who want to read instead of listening:
Eric Berger: How did you go so fast?
Elon Musk: I have this mantra: if the schedule is long, it&amp;rsquo;s wrong.</description></item><item><title>Deploying an application using Dokku (with https and redirects)</title><link>https://vblinden.nl/posts/deploying-an-application-using-dokku-with-https-and-redirects/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2020 13:39:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://vblinden.nl/posts/deploying-an-application-using-dokku-with-https-and-redirects/</guid><description>If you are creating a web application, you have to deploy it at some point. Most of the time I choose a service or provider that manages the server for me and I just have to deploy the application. Think about Heroku, Fortrabbit, Google Cloud, Microsoft Azure or AWS. These services are great and work really well, however they can really add up in cost when you want to scale up an application or have multiple little applications running.</description></item><item><title>Setup Let's Encrypt with Nginx</title><link>https://vblinden.nl/posts/setup-lets-encrypt-with-nginx/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2019 19:31:13 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://vblinden.nl/posts/setup-lets-encrypt-with-nginx/</guid><description>When I migrated my VPS (with Ubuntu) to an other host, I needed to setup Nginx again with Let&amp;rsquo;s Encrypt but I always forget how to exactly do it. This blog post is aimed to describe in easy steps how to setup up Nginx with auto-renewing Let&amp;rsquo;s Encrypt SSL certificates.
Setting up Nginx Setting up Nginx is super easy on Ubuntu. Run the following commands on your VPS.
sudo apt update sudo apt install nginx If you have a firewall (ufw) enabled run the following command to enable HTTP (80) and HTTPS (443) to the firewall.</description></item><item><title>Retrieve submodules with Git</title><link>https://vblinden.nl/posts/retrieve-submodules-with-git/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2019 17:06:13 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://vblinden.nl/posts/retrieve-submodules-with-git/</guid><description>Yesterday I had a really difficult time with pulling in a submodule from an old git repository I had laying around. I thought a quick Google DuckDuckGo search would solve all my problems, but alas. There was a lot of outdated information that simply didn&amp;rsquo;t work with the Git version I had installed on my computer (or I applied incorrectly).
Finally I found a answer on StackOverflow1 that put me in the right direction, but that also didn&amp;rsquo;t work.</description></item><item><title>Never. Forget. Backups.</title><link>https://vblinden.nl/posts/never-forget-backups/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2019 14:57:59 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://vblinden.nl/posts/never-forget-backups/</guid><description>Unfortunately DigitalOcean had a node failure yesterday in their AMS3 data center. And sadly my virtual machine running my blog was on there and I didn&amp;rsquo;t have backups enabled. So all my data is permanently gone. Which is not a huge problem, because I only had two small blog posts on here.
So today I decided to make my blog a static website using Hugo.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://vblinden.nl/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vblinden.nl/about/</guid><description>My nickname is vblinden and I work as a sofware engineer. On my site you can find some thoughts and other babbling that I thought were important enough to put online.
Disclaimer: The opinions expressed herein are my own personal opinions and do not represent my employer’s view in any way.</description></item><item><title>Projects</title><link>https://vblinden.nl/projects/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vblinden.nl/projects/</guid><description>These are some pet projects I like to work on in my free time.
checkify.io Super minimal and simple 24/7 uptime monitoring service. Create an account, add an url, and it will check it every 10 minutes for free. When the url is down, it will notify you via email. It also offers 1 minute checks for a small fee.
nederboard.nl A soundboard with snippets from all kinds of different meme videos in the Netherlands.</description></item></channel></rss>